A Guide to the Ford Foundation records, Administration, Building Services, Ford Foundation Headquarters, New Building Planning and Construction Files FA500
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Building Services, 1951-1998, bulk 1964-1969; 1964-1969; V; 3.23 Cubic Feet
  - Phil Kemp Building Files [microfilm], undated (Box 49, Folder 9)
  - Policy for Contractor's Advertising -- Memoranda, 1968 January 2-March 6 (Box 49, Folder 10)
  - Receptionists -- Memoranda Re: Planning, 1965 November 25-1966 July 28 (Box 49, Folder 11)
  - Restaurant Correspondence -- Photographs (separated) Re: Architectural Record Feb 1969 Article (Box 49, Folder 12)
  - Security -- New Building Requirements -- Memoranda and Correspondence, 1965 (Box 49, Folder 13)
  - Staff Memoranda from Gertrude Winquist, 1966 July-1968 May (Box 49, Folder 14)
  - Sub-Lease -- 477 Madison Avenue -- Barbet and Weigert Advertising Inc. -- 16th Floor, 1967 December 20 (Box 49, Folder 15)
  - Sub-Lease -- 477 Madison Avenue -- City Investing Co. -- 19th Floor -- Lease and Correspondence Re: Litigation, 1967 December 11-1970 April 15 (Box 62, Folder 8)
  - Sub-Lease -- 477 Madison Avenue -- Educational Facilities Labs, Inc. -- 20th Floor, 1967 December 1-1968 February 12 (Box 62, Folder 9)
  - Sub-Lease -- 477 Madison Avenue -- Engelhard Industries -- 24th Floor, 1966 June 27 (Box 49, Folder 16)
  - Sub-Lease -- 477 Madison Avenue -- Esaress International Group -- 15th Floor, 1968 April 3 (Box 50, Folder 1)
  - Sub-Lease -- 477 Madison Avenue -- LIN Broadcasting Corp. -- 17th Floor, 1968 April 3 (Box 50, Folder 2)
  - Sub-Lease -- 477 Madison Avenue -- The Merchandising Group -- 16th Floor, 1968 April 4 (Box 50, Folder 3)
  - Sub-Lease -- 477 Madison Avenue -- Paul Klemtner and Co., Inc. -- 24th Floor, 1967 September 12 (Box 50, Folder 4)
  - Sub-Lease -- 477 Madison Avenue -- Phillips, Nizer, Benjamin, Krim and Ballon -- 11th and 12th Floors, 1968 May 10 (Box 50, Folder 5)
  - Sub-Lease -- 477 Madison Avenue -- Toshiba America, Inc., 1967 October 31-1968 April 3 (Box 62, Folder 10)
  - Sub-Lease -- 477 Madison Avenue -- Vernitron Corp., 1967 October 10-1968 April 3 (Box 62, Folder 11)
  - Suggested Stationary -- Samples, 1967 September 15 (Box 50, Folder 6)
  - Supervisory System -- Security Alarms -- Agreement, 1965 November 12-1966 November 18 (Box 50, Folder 7)
  - Taxes and Tax Exemptions -- Correspondence, Notes, Forms and Background Re: Tax Exemptions, 1951 September 13-1967 March 13 (Box 50, Folder 8)
  - Title Insurance, 1965 October-1966 May (Box 50, Folder 9)
  - Tours -- Memoranda and Notes Re: Planning, 1965 August 22-1966 July 18 (Box 50, Folder 10)
  - Tours -- Memoranda and Group Lists, 1966-1968 (Box 50, Folder 11)
  - UNIVAC -- Agreement, Memoranda, Purchase Orders, Data, 1955-1965 (Box 50, Folder 12)
  - Violations -- Correspondence Re: Occupancy, 1967 August 10-1968 April 29 (Box 50, Folder 13)
- Images, 1963-1999, bulk 1963-1968; 1963-1968; VI; 6.56 Cubic Feet
  Series VI. Images, 1965-1988 (bulk 1965-1968)
  This series contains visual documentation (slides, photographs, negatives and contact sheets) of the construction and completion of the Ford Foundation Headquarters Building, and its 20th Anniversary in 1987. The majority of the slides depict construction, including site preparation, pouring of the concrete foundation, welding and riveting, fireproofing and electrical work. Additional slides from the same period show the granite quarry in New England that supplied stone for the building, while others portray models of office furnishings. There also are photographs of the building once it was fully staffed and the atrium garden planted (c.1968). Other photographs show the building atrium in December 1970 and the atrium and building exterior in September 1988. In addition, there are a number of contact sheets with images of the various stages of construction and architect Kevin Roche. The photographers were Eugene Cook and Bruce Davidson. Additional photographs, some used in Life magazine, have been separated and retained in frames.
  - Contact Sheets -- Auditorium -- Eugene Cook, circa 1966 (Box 51, Folder 1)
  - Contact Sheets -- Auditorium, etc. -- Eugene Cook, circa 1966 (Box 51, Folder 2)
  - Contact Sheets -- Construction -- Eugene Cook (1 of 3), circa 1966 (Box 51, Folder 3)
  - Contact Sheets -- Construction -- Eugene Cook (2 of 3), circa 1966 (Box 51, Folder 4)
  - Contact Sheets -- Construction -- Eugene Cook (3 of 3), circa 1966 (Box 51, Folder 5)
  - Contact Sheets -- Construction -- Various -- Eugene Cook (1 of 3), 1965 December 1-7 (Box 51, Folder 6)
  - Contact Sheets -- Construction -- Various -- Eugene Cook (2 of 3), circa 1965-1966 (Box 51, Folder 7)
  - Contact Sheets -- Construction -- Various -- Eugene Cook (3 of 3), 1966 January 25-30 (Box 51, Folder 8)
  - Contact Sheets -- Construction -- Duplicates -- Eugene Cook, circa 1966 (Box 51, Folder 9)
  - Contact Sheets -- Construction -- Bruce Davidson (1 of 4), 1968 (Box 51, Folder 10)
  - Contact Sheets -- Construction -- Bruce Davidson (2 of 4), 1968 (Box 51, Folder 11)
  - Contact Sheets -- Construction -- Bruce Davidson (3 of 4), 1968 (Box 51, Folder 12)
  - Contact Sheets -- Construction -- Bruce Davidson (4 of 4), 1968 (Box 52, Folder 1)
  - Contact Sheets -- Construction -- Designers, Atrium Completion -- Bruce Davidson/Magnum Films, 1966 (Box 52, Folder 2)
  - Contact Sheets -- Construction -- Kevin Roche -- Bruce Davidson, 1968 (Box 52, Folder 3)
  - Contact Sheets -- Full View of Site -- Eugene Cook, circa 1966 (Box 52, Folder 4)
  - Contact Sheets -- Full View of Site -- Eugene Cook, 1966 April 22-30 (Box 52, Folder 5)
  - Contact Sheets -- Laying Pipe -- Eugene Cook, circa 1966 (Box 52, Folder 6)
  - Contact Sheets -- Kevin Roche -- Eugene Cook, circa 1966 (Box 52, Folder 7)
  - Contact Sheets -- Stairs and Stairwell -- 3rd Floor -- Eugene Cook, circa 1966-1967 (Box 52, Folder 8)
  - Contact Sheets -- Unidentified -- Move In?, circa 1967 (Box 52, Folder 9)
  - Contact Sheets -- Widest Views of Building -- Eugene Cook, 1966 January 18-19 (Box 52, Folder 10)
  - Negatives -- 320 East 43rd St. -- 1-109 -- Site Preparation and Hospital Demolition, 1963 August 26-1964 May 16 (Box 53, Folder 1)
  - Negatives -- 320 East 43rd St. -- 110-242 -- Demolition and Foundation Work, 1964 May 19-1965 April 29 (Box 53, Folder 2)
  - Negatives -- 320 East 43rd St. -- 243-383, 1965 May 6-December 23 (Box 53, Folder 3)
  - Negatives -- 320 East 43rd St. -- 384-551, 1965 December 30-1966 November 17 (Box 53, Folder 4)
  - Negatives -- 320 East 43rd St. -- 552-694, 1966 December 1-1967 October 26 (Box 53, Folder 5)
  - Negatives -- Color -- Bridge View, circa 1966 (Box 53, Folder 6)
  - Negatives -- Color -- Building Inspectors Looking Through Fence, etc., undated (Box 53, Folder 7)
  - Negatives -- Color -- Closeup Views of Site, View From Bridge, circa 1966 (Box 53, Folder 8)
  - Negatives -- Color -- North Side 43rd Street, Full View, Floor -- Eugene Cook, circa 1966 (Box 53, Folder 9)
  - Negatives -- Ford Foundation Headquarters -- "Deliver To Mr. Kemp" -- Eugene Cook, circa 1966 (Box 53, Folder 10)
  - Negatives -- Ford Foundation Headquarters -- Trustees Dining Room in Construction, Jun 23 or Sep 27; unknown year (Box 53, Folder 11)
  - Negatives -- Ford Foundation Headquarters -- Various, Sep 27; unknown year (Box 53, Folder 12)
  - Negatives -- New Building -- William Simmons -- Ford Foundation 431 Rolls A and B 35 mm -- Building Model 4x5 Negatives, 1965 May (Box 53, Folder 13)
  - Photos -- 320 East 43rd St. -- Building Extension Final Installation Work -- A-F, 691-694, 1967 March 9-October 26 (Box 54, Folder 1)
  - Photos -- 320 East 43rd St. -- Foundation Preparation -- 147-169, 1964 July 8-December 31 (Box 54, Folder 2)
  - Photos -- 320 East 43rd St. -- Foundation Construction -- 171-323, 1965 January 7-September 16 (Box 54, Folder 3)
  - Photos -- 320 East 43rd St. -- Site Demolition -- 1-17, 1963 August 26-September 19 (Box 54, Folder 4)
  - Photos -- 320 East 43rd St. -- Site Demolition -- 18-37, 1963 October 29-November 26 (Box 54, Folder 5)
  - Photos -- 320 East 43rd St. -- Site Demolition -- 39-58, 1963 December 6-21 (Box 54, Folder 6)
  - Photos -- 320 East 43rd St. -- Site Demolition -- 73-84, 1963 December 31-1964 May 11 (Box 55, Folder 1)
  - Photos -- 320 East 43rd St. -- Site Demolition -- 88-109, 1964 May 16 (Box 55, Folder 2)
  - Photos -- 320 East 43rd St. -- Site Demolition -- 110-125, 1964 May 19-June 8 (Box 55, Folder 3)
  - Photos -- 320 East 43rd St. -- Site Demolition -- 127-146, 1964 June 15-27 (Box 55, Folder 4)
  - Photos -- Board Room Entrance -- Esto, circa 1968 (Box 55, Folder 5)
  - Photos -- Building -- Magnum -- Bruce Davidson, 1966 (Box 64, Folder 1)
  - Photos -- Building Construction -- Black and White -- Eugene Cook, circa 1966 (Box 66, Folder 3)
  - Photos -- Building Construction -- Black and White -- Eugene Cook -- Unidentified Building, circa 1966 (Box 64, Folder 5)
  - Photos -- Building Construction -- Color, circa 1966 (Box 66, Folder 2)
  - Photos -- Building Construction -- Color -- Posterboard Backed, 1966 June 20 (Box 66, Folder 1)
  - Photos -- Building Construction -- Completion -- Artwork -- Garden -- Posterboard Backed -- UPI, circa 1968 (Box 64, Folder 6)
  - Photos -- Building Exterior from 42nd St. -- With Negatives -- Ezra Stoller, circa 1967 (Box 55, Folder 6)
  - Photos -- Carpenters, circa 1965 (Box 55, Folder 7)
  - Photos -- Cementing -- First Slab -- Eugene Cook, 1965 September (Box 55, Folder 8)
  - Photos -- Cementing -- Slab -- Eugene Cook, 1965 October 25 (Box 55, Folder 9)
  - Photos -- Cementing and Foundation, undated (Box 55, Folder 10)
  - Photos -- Cementing Slab, undated (Box 56, Folder 1)
  - Photos -- Column-Steel Reforms for Column -- Eugene Cook, undated (Box 56, Folder 2)
  - Photos -- Dining Room -- Esto, circa 1968 (Box 56, Folder 3)
  - Photos -- Electricians Working on Slab, circa 1965 (Box 56, Folder 4)
  - Photos -- Ezra Stoller Associates -- Building (see also: Slides), circa 1968 (Box 56, Folder 5)
  - Photos -- Finishing Slab -- Leveling Concrete, circa 1965 (Box 56, Folder 6)
  - Photos -- Ford Foundation Headquarters Exterior -- Glassboro State College Art Project -- With Negatives, 1977 (Box 56, Folder 7)
  - Photos -- Form Work for Wall and Slab, circa 1965 (Box 56, Folder 8)
  - Photos -- Form Work -- Mainly on Walls, circa 1965 (Box 56, Folder 9)
  - Photos -- Forms for Retaining Wall, undated (Box 56, Folder 10)
  - Photos -- Foundation Work -- Looking South and Southeast, circa 1965 (Box 56, Folder 11)
  - Photos -- Foundation Work -- Looking West, circa 1965 (Box 56, Folder 12)
  - Photos -- Foundation Work -- Looking West -- Color Transparency and Black and White Photographs, 1965 November (Box 56, Folder 13)
  - Photos -- Garage Slab, 1965 September 15-16 (Box 56, Folder 14)
  - Photos -- Garden -- Bruce Davidson, circa 1968 (Box 56, Folder 15)
  - Photos -- Garden -- Negatives Included -- Ezra Stoller, 1967 (Box 56, Folder 16)
  - Photos -- Garden -- Posterboard Backed -- David Lawrence, circa 1968 (Box 64, Folder 2)
  - Photos -- Garden and Plantings -- Dan Kiley -- Dedication Party? -- Contact Prints, circa 1968 (Box 56, Folder 17)
  - Photos -- Garden in Progress -- Bruce Davidson, circa 1966 (Box 57, Folder 1)
  - Photos -- Human Interest (1 of 2), undated (Box 57, Folder 2)
  - Photos -- Human Interest (2 of 2), undated (Box 57, Folder 3)
  - Photos -- Human Interest -- Foundation and Structural Work, undated (Box 57, Folder 4)
  - Photos -- Human Interest -- Foundation and Support Work, undated (Box 57, Folder 5)
  - Photos -- Human Interest -- Foundation Work, undated (Box 57, Folder 6)
  - Photos -- John V. Dinan -- 800 Second Avenue (1 of 3), 1964 April 13 (Box 57, Folder 7)
  - Photos -- John V. Dinan -- 330 E. 43rd St. Sidewalk, North Side, E. 43rd St. (2 of 3), 1964 April 13 (Box 57, Folder 8)
  - Photos -- John V. Dinan -- Sidewalks, Curbs, E. 43rd St., 303 and 303 1/2 E. 43rd St., 305-309, 313, 321 E. 43rd St., Retaining Wall, Site (3 of 3), 1964 April 13 (Box 57, Folder 9)
  - Photos -- Looking East or Southeast -- Eugene Cook, circa 1965 (Box 58, Folder 1)
  - Photos -- Looking East or Southeast -- Black and White Photographs, Color Transparencies -- Eugene Cook, 1965 October 28 (Box 58, Folder 2)
  - Photos -- Looking North -- Includes Color Transparencies -- Eugene Cook, circa 1965 (Box 58, Folder 3)
  - Photos -- Looking South -- Color Transparencies -- Eugene Cook, circa 1965 (Box 58, Folder 4)
  - Photos -- Looking South -- Contact Sheets and Color Transparencies -- Eugene Cook, 1965 October-November (Box 58, Folder 5)
  - Photos -- Main Conference Room/Auditorium -- Esto, circa 1968 (Box 58, Folder 6)
  - Photos -- Model of New Building -- Ezra Stoller (1 of 2), undated (Box 58, Folder 7)
  - Photos -- Model of New Building -- Ezra Stoller (2 of 2), undated (Box 58, Folder 8)
  - Photos -- Model of New Building from 42nd and 43rd Streets -- Eric Pollitzer, undated (Box 58, Folder 9)
  - Photos -- Neighboring Structures -- Water Seepage from 800 Second Avenue (A-F) -- Mal Gurian, 1967 March 9 (Box 58, Folder 10)
  - Photos -- New Building -- Ezra Stoller and Malcolm Smith, circa 1962-1967 (Box 58, Folder 11)
  - Photos -- New Building Model -- Posterboard Backed, circa 1966 (Box 64, Folder 4)
  - Photos -- New York Times Article, 1967 (Box 58, Folder 12)
  - Photos -- Office of the Secretary -- Building of the Ford Foundation -- Building Committee -- Building Public Relations Photographs, circa 1968 (Box 58, Folder 13)
  - Photos -- Parks Department Application -- Pictures of Wall to be Demolished -- Mal Gurian/Ed Whitey, 1963 July 24-December 6 (Box 58, Folder 14)
  - Photos -- Pouring Concrete -- Eugene Cook, undated (Box 58, Folder 15)
  - Photos -- President's Office -- Esto, circa 1967 (Box 58, Folder 16)
  - Photos -- Reception Area -- Esto, circa 1968 (Box 58, Folder 17)
  - Photos -- Reinforcement -- Placing Beam in Site, undated (Box 58, Folder 18)
  - Photos -- Reinforcing for Column, undated (Box 58, Folder 19)
  - Photos -- Reinforcing for Slab, circa 1965 (Box 58, Folder 20)
  - Photos -- Reports -- Re-examination -- 328-334 East 34th Street -- Hermitage, 1965 September 20 (Box 58, Folder 21)
  - Photos -- Reports -- Re-examination -- 800 Second Avenue, 1965 September 20 (Box 58, Folder 22)
  - Photos -- Reports -- Re-examination -- East 43rd Street Areas, 1965 October 20 (Box 58, Folder 23)
  - Photos -- Restaurant -- Cafeteria, 1969 (Box 58, Folder 24)
  - Photos -- Retaining Wall, circa 1965 (Box 58, Folder 25)
  - Photos -- Roche, Kevin -- Plans and Model -- Eugene Cook, 1965 September (Box 58, Folder 26)
  - Photos -- Setting Up Beam Site, circa 1965 (Box 58, Folder 27)
  - Photos -- Tudor City Sixth Unit -- Hermitage from Ford Foundation Lot (#100) Looking East 2pm -- Mal Gurian, 1964 May 16 (Box 58, Folder 28)
  - Prints -- Area Maps, circa 1971 (Box 64, Folder 8)
  - Prints -- Building Sketch and Brochure Cover Art -- Posterboard Backed, circa 1971 (Box 64, Folder 7)
  - Prints -- Ina Taylor's Gift (flipped), 1999 February 25 (Box 59, Folder 1)
  - Prints -- UDC Feasibility Study Projections and Blueprints -- Blueprints -- Edward Barnes, 1973 August 22 (Box 64, Folder 9)
  - Prints -- UDC Feasibility Study Projections and Blueprints -- Posterboard -- Edward Barnes (1 of 2), 1973 August 22 (Box 65, Folder 1)
  - Prints -- UDC Feasibility Study Projections and Blueprints -- Posterboard -- Edward Barnes (2 of 2), 1973 August 22 (Box 65, Folder 2)
  - Slides -- Atrium and Exterior, 1988 September (Box 59, Folder 2)
  - Slides -- Building Miscellaneous -- Atrium and 10th Floor, circa 1970 December (Box 59, Folder 3)
  - Slides -- Construction -- Eugene Cook, 1965 November-1966 April (Box 59, Folder 4)
  - Slides -- Construction -- Cement Work, Furnishings (Secretarial), etc. -- Eugene Cook, 1965 October (Box 59, Folder 5)
  - Slides -- Construction -- Overall, Auditorium, Fireproofing, etc., 1966 April-June (Box 59, Folder 6)
  - Slides -- Construction and Granite Quarry -- Eugene Cook, 1965 August (Box 59, Folder 7)
  - Slides -- Cor-Ten Weathering Samples at 12th Floor 800 Second Avenue -- Mal Gurian Associates, Photographers -- 4 35mm Color Transparencies, 1966 March 17 (Box 59, Folder 8)
  - Slides -- Miscellaneous Building Slides from Broken Sets in Numerical Order -- Ezra Stoller Associates, Inc. -- Esto, circa 1968 (Box 59, Folder 9)
  - Slides -- Model of New Building -- With Prints, undated (Box 59, Folder 10)
  - Slides -- New Building Exterior and Garden -- From Robert Mayer, circa 1967 (Box 59, Folder 11)